Hey there, have you ever felt a little stuck trying to ask where in English?
こんにちは、英語で「どこ」と聞くのが ちょっと難しいと感じたことはありますか？
You know, it can seem tricky, but what if I told you it all comes down to just two simple
難しそうに見えるかもしれませんが、 実はたった2つのシンプルな
rules?
ルールに集約されます。
In this explainer, we're going to break them down so you can ask where questions perfectly
この説明では、それを分解して どこを聞く質問を完璧にする方法を
every single time.
お教えします。
So let's start with a classic question we've all asked.
まずは、みんなが一度は聞いたことのある クラシックな質問から始めましょう。
Where is my key?
私の鍵はどこですか？
This one little question holds the secret, no pun intended, to understanding the
この小さな質問には、全体の構造を 理解するための秘密が隠されています。
whole structure.
冗談ではなく。
Once you get this down, you can ask pretty much anything with confidence.
これを理解すれば、自信を持って ほとんど何でも聞けるようになります。
Let's dive right in.
さあ、始めましょう。
Alright, our first stop is the most common and, honestly, the most straightforward type
最初のポイントは、最も一般的で、 正直言って最も簡単なタイプの
of where question.
「どこ」の質問です。
This is the rule for when you're using what we call B verbs.
これは、私たちがB動詞と呼ぶものを 使うときのルールです。
So what exactly are B verbs?
B動詞とは一体何でしょうか？
Well, they're words like is, are, was, and were.
それは、is、are、was、wereのような 言葉です。
The most important thing to remember is they don't describe an action, like running or
最も重要なのは、これらは 動作を表すのではなく、
eating.
存在の状態を表します。
Nope, they just describe a state of being, you know, where something exists.
つまり、何かがどこにあるかを示すのです。
Let's see how this works in action.
これがどのように機能するか見てみましょう。
We start with a simple statement, the answer. Your key is on the desk.
まずはシンプルな文、答えから始めます。 あなたの鍵は机の上にあります。
First, we just take the place on the desk and swap it with our question word, where.
まず、机の上という場所を 質問の言葉「どこ」と入れ替えます。
Now it says, your key is where, which sounds a little weird, right?
すると、「あなたの鍵はどこ？」となりますが、 ちょっと変ですよね？
So here's the magic step.
ここがポイントです。
We move where all the way to the front and then we just flip the subject and the verb.
「どこ」を一番前に持ってきて、 主語と動詞を入れ替えます。
So your key is becomes, is your key?
「あなたの鍵は」が「あなたの鍵は？」に。
And of course you gotta match the verb to whatever you're talking about.
もちろん、動詞は話している内容に合わせる必要があります。
If you're asking about one thing, like my phone, you use is.
一つのもの、例えば「私の電話」について聞くときは、isを使います。
If you're asking about more than one thing, like your shoes, you use are.
複数のもの、例えば「あなたの靴」について聞くときは、areを使います。
And this exact same logic works for the past tense, too.
この論理は過去形にも同じように適用されます。
For one thing, you'd ask where was my phone?
一つのものについては「私の電話はどこにあった？」と聞き、
And for many, where were your shoes? It's that simple.
複数のものについては「あなたの靴はどこにあった？」となります。 それだけ簡単です。
Okay, so that was rule one. Pretty easy, right?
さて、これがルール1です。簡単でしたね？
But what happens when you want to ask where an action is happening?
では、動作が行われている場所を 聞きたいときはどうしますか？
Well, that brings us to our second rule, and this one covers all those other verbs.
それが私たちの第二のルールで、 こちらは他の動詞をカバーします。
Now, here's the big difference.
ここが大きな違いです。
pay close attention. With a B verb, we saw the verb itself, like is, actually moves. But
注意してください。B動詞では、動詞自体が 実際に動きますが、
for an action verb, like live, the verb stays put. Instead, we have to bring in a helper
動作動詞、例えば「住む」では、 動詞はそのままです。代わりに、
verb, and in this case, it's do. This little helper word is the key to this entire structure.
助動詞を使う必要があり、 この場合はdoです。この小さな助動詞が
Let's break that one down too. We'll start with the answer again. They live in Sydney.
この全体の構造の鍵です。
Now, to turn this into a question, we first add our helper, do, right at the beginning.
もう一度分解してみましょう。 答えから始めます。彼らはシドニーに住んでいます。
Do they live in Sydney?
これを質問にするために、 まず助動詞doを最初に加えます。
Then just like before, we replace the place with where and pop it right at the front.
「彼らはシドニーに住んでいますか？」
And we get, where do they live? Did you see that?
そして、前と同じように、場所を「どこ」に 置き換えて前に持ってきます。
The main verb, live, didn't move an inch.
すると、「彼らはどこに住んでいますか？」になります。 わかりましたか？
The helper, do, did all the heavy lefting.
主要な動詞「住む」は全く動いていません。
So how do you pick the right helper verb? It's actually really simple.
助動詞doが全ての重荷を背負っています。
For subjects like I, you, we, and they, you're going to use do.
では、正しい助動詞を選ぶにはどうすればいいのでしょうか？ 実はとても簡単です。
For a single person or thing, you know, he, she, or it, you use does.
主語がI、you、we、theyの場合はdoを使います。
And for anything that happened in the past, it's always did.
一人の人や物、つまりhe、she、itの場合はdoesを使います。
Doesn't matter what the subject is, it's always did.
過去に起こったことについては、 常にdidです。
Okay, so you've got the two rules, now it's time to put them to the test.
主語が何であれ、常にdidです。
I'll show you a few questions and your job is to just think about what the answer might
さて、2つのルールを理解したので、 テストしてみましょう。
look like. You ready? Let's do this. First one up.
いくつかの質問をお見せしますので、 あなたの仕事は答えがどうなるか考えることです。
Where is Mr. Brown from? So take a look.
準備はいいですか？始めましょう。 最初の質問です。
We see the verb IS, so we know right away this is a BE verb question.
ブラウンさんはどこ出身ですか？ 見てみましょう。
That means the answer is going to follow our first simple rule.
動詞はISなので、すぐに これはB動詞の質問だとわかります。
Let's see what it is.
つまり、答えは 最初のシンプルなルールに従います。
there it is. He's from the USA. You see how the is from the question is right there in the answer?
さあ、答えを見てみましょう。 彼はアメリカ出身です。
His is just short for he is. It's a perfect match.
質問のisが答えの中に そのまま入っていますね。
All right, next question. Where does Naomi live? Okay, what clues are we seeing here?
次の質問です。ナオミはどこに住んでいますか？ どんな手がかりが見えますか？
We've got the helper verb does and the action verb live. What does that tell you about how the
助動詞の「does」と動詞の「live」があります。これから答えがどうなるか分かりますか？
answer should be formed? And the answer is she lives in Narita. Now notice the connection.
答えは「彼女は成田に住んでいます」です。ここに関連性があります。
Because the question uses does, the verb in the answer, live, gets that S on the end.
質問に「does」が使われているので、答えの動詞「live」は「lives」になります。
So, does live becomes lives. That's the pattern you're looking for.
「does live」は「lives」になるのです。これが探しているパターンです。
Let's try another one with does. Where does this bus go?
では、もう一つ「does」を使った例を試しましょう。バスはどこに行きますか？
Again, we can see that helper verb doing its job. Think for a second.
また、助動詞がその役割を果たしています。少し考えてみてください。
How is that verb go going to change in the answer?
答えでは「go」はどう変わりますか？
And there we go. It goes to Chiba Station. See? Once again, the helper does in the question
そうです。「千葉駅に行きます」となります。見えましたか？質問の「does」が
is a signal that the answer's verb becomes goes. It's a really consistent rule.
答えの動詞を「goes」にする合図です。これは非常に一貫したルールです。
Okay, what about this one? Where does Tom study? It's the same pattern just with a different
では、次はこれです。トムはどこで勉強していますか？同じパターンですが、
action verb. What do you think? The answer, of course, is he studies in the library.
異なる動詞です。どう思いますか？答えは「彼は図書館で勉強しています」です。
The verb study changes to studies. This really shows how that little helper verb does is
動詞「study」は「studies」に変わります。この小さな助動詞「does」が
basically a signal for how you need to form the answer. Last one for practice. Let's bring
答えの形成方法を示しています。最後の練習問題です。最初に戻りましょう。
it all the way back to the beginning. Where is Mary now? Which one of our two rules are we using
メアリーは今どこにいますか？どちらのルールを使っていますか？
here? And the answer is, she's in the kitchen now. We're back to our simple beaver rule. The
答えは「彼女は今キッチンにいます」です。シンプルなbe動詞のルールに戻りました。
question uses is and the answer uses she's, which is just she is. You totally nailed it.
質問は「is」を使い、答えは「she's」、つまり「she is」です。完璧です。
Fantastic work. Okay, you've seen both rules and you've aced the practice. Now let's put it
素晴らしい仕事です。両方のルールを見て、練習も完璧でしたね。では、
it all together on one simple, easy-to- read cheat sheet.
簡単に読めるチートシートにまとめましょう。
This chart lays out our two rules side by side, making it super clear.
このチャートは二つのルールを並べて示し、とても分かりやすくしています。
Up top, you've got the B verbs.
上にはbe動詞があります。
It's just where plus a B verb like is or are or their past tense buddies was and
「where」プラス「is」や「are」、過去形の「was」や「were」と主語が続きます。
were followed by the subject.
その下には一般動詞があります。
Then down below, you've got the general verbs.
「where」プラス「do」や「does」、過去形の「did」、その後に主語、
It's where plus a helper like do or does or the past tense did, then the subject
そして主動詞が続きます。これがあなたの鍵です。
and then the main verb. This is your key.
だから「私の眼鏡はどこ？」や「彼らはどこで遊んだ？」と聞くとき、公式はここにあります。
here for you.
これが英語で「where」を尋ねるための二つのシンプルなルールです。
So there you have it, the two simple rules for asking where in English.
結局は一つの質問に集約されます。
It really just comes down to one question.
be動詞を使っていますか、それとも動作動詞ですか？
Are you using a B-verb or an action verb?
最後に一つだけ質問があります。
And that leaves me with just one final question for you.
ルールを理解した今、今日誰かに最初に聞く「where」は何ですか？